<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on My Blog</title><link>https://goiw111.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on My Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>souhail-chahmout</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goiw111.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Musical Synthesizer with FPGA and VHDL: A Step-by-Step Guide</title><link>https://goiw111.github.io/posts/n_2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goiw111.github.io/posts/n_2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://goiw111.github.io/images/N_2_5.jpg" alt="N_2_5">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project wasn’t just about making music with hardware – it was a &lt;strong>hardware detective story&lt;/strong>. Armed with an ancient Chinese FPGA board and zero documentation, I accepted my professor’s challenge to breathe life into forgotten technology. Here’s how I turned frustration into a functional synthesizer!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="key-design-insights">&lt;strong>Key Design Insights&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="why-higher-frequencies">&lt;strong>Why Higher Frequencies?&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Passive buzzers struggle with low frequencies (e.g., 262 Hz for middle C). By targeting &lt;strong>C5–C6&lt;/strong> (523–1047 Hz), we:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Obsidian Notes to Hugo Blog Posts. My Automated Publishing Workflow</title><link>https://goiw111.github.io/posts/n_1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goiw111.github.io/posts/n_1/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a master’s student, I rely on Obsidian for organizing my research notes, ideas, and resources—its graph view and local-first approach make it perfect for long-term knowledge management. But when I want to share polished articles, I use Hugo, a fast and flexible static site generator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem? Manually converting Obsidian notes into Hugo-ready Markdown was tedious. I needed a way to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Convert &lt;code>[[wikilinks]] → [Markdown links](/posts/slug)&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transform &lt;code>![[image.png]] → ![](/images/image.png)&lt;/code>and copy images to /static/images&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-generate title and date in front matter while preserving existing YAML
So, I built an Obsidian plugin to automate this process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here’s how it works, step by step.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>